# ADOLF SCHMUCK

Email: adolf.schmuck@gmail.com | Phone: 619-750-9469 | San Diego, CA 91977

GitHub: https://github.com/answebdev | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adolf-schmuck/

Portfolio: https://adolfschmuck.com/

Web developer with over 10 years of experience in ESL instruction currently focusing on building clean, savvy applications. Seeking to use proven skills in coding and collaboration to meet the needs of projects involving both front-end and back-end technology. An experienced professional with a superb work ethic passionate about developing great products as a front-end web developer.

**Technical Skills:** HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, JavaScript, jQuery, GIT, the command line, GitHub, Node.js, NPM, Express.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, and Heroku.

#### **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

## The Simpsons Clicky Game (Role: React Developer)

- A React application that tests your memory with a Simpsons-themed memory game.
- Languages and technology used: React.js, ES6, NPM packages: ReactHowler and SweetAlert, Bootstrap, and CSS.
- Deployed application: <a href="https://answebdev.github.io/clicky-game/">https://answebdev.github.io/clicky-game/</a>

## Eat-Da-Burger! (Role: Full-stack Developer)

- A full-stack restaurant application that allows users to input the names of burgers they'd like to eat; burgers are kept in the waiting area until they are eaten.
- Languages and technology used: Express.js, Node.js, Handlebars, MySQL, homemade ORM, AJAX/APIs, jQuery, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Deployed application: https://radiant-island-72390.herokuapp.com/

#### LIRI Bot (Role: Back-end Developer)

- A command line Node app that allows the user to search for songs, concerts, and movies.
- Languages and technology used: Node.js; the command line; APIs from Bands In Town, Spotify, and OMBD; NPM packages: fs, Moment, Request, and the Node-Spotify-API.
- Video demo: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zTTCWQ063xKTVHmKXtmQ4XHE-XpSAP 5/view

#### Bar Finder (Role: Front-end Developer on a team of four)

- A web application that allows the user to search for a bar based on location and bar type, as well as search for drink recipes.
- Languages and technology used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery; Bootstrap, Semantic UI; Firebase: AJAX; APIs from Open Brewery DB, TheCocktailDB, and Google Maps.
- Deployed application: <a href="https://brysonelson.github.io/project-gpqp/">https://brysonelson.github.io/project-gpqp/</a>

#### **Train Scheduler (Role: Front-end Developer)**

- An application that provides up-to-date information about various trains, namely their arrival times and how many minutes remain until they arrive at their station.
- Languages and technology used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery, Firebase, and Moment.js.
- Deployed application: https://answebdev.github.io/TrainScheduler/

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Grossmont College, El Cajon, CA**

Professor Adjunct, January 2016 - Present

- Teaching students the skills needed to speak accurately and with an understandable accent when using the basic language functions needed to communicate effectively in college.
- Helping ESL college students develop basic listening and grammatically accurate speaking skills appropriate in an academic setting.
- Organizing and delivering well-developed lesson plans with attention to detail and creativity.
- Collaborating with co-instructors to fully assist students registered in corequisite courses.

#### Mesa College (UCSD), San Diego, CA

Professor Adjunct, August 2015 - December 2015

- Taught Basic Writing (ESOL) to university students in order to prepare them for the challenges of the UCSD College Writing Programs.
- Taught students the skills needed to produce academic papers, culminating in the submission of a final portfolio.
- Led and conducted writing workshops for students to practice revision and editing using feedback from instructor and peers.

# EC San Diego, La Jolla, CA

ESL Instructor, February 2012 – Present

- Teaching adults of various nationalities and a wide range of skill levels in a setting in which all language skills (from pronunciation to grammatical structures) are employed.
- Designing and delivering engaging lesson plans that keep students motivated and engaged.
- Additional duties include giving students one-on-one monthly tutorials, preparing student assessment reports, and writing letters of recommendation for students.

#### Pagoda Academy, Seoul, South Korea

EFL Instructor, January 2011 - December 2011

- Taught conversation and academic classes to adults of a wide range of skill levels.
- Prepared and wrote monthly assessment reports that evaluated students with an emphasis on skills transferable to other classes and contexts.
- Conducted level placement interviews for prospective students.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### UC San Diego Extension, La Jolla, CA

Full Stack Coding Boot Camp Certificate, August 2018 – February 2019
An intensive six-month long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, and React.js.

#### San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

Master of Arts in Linguistics

#### San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

Basic Certificate in Applied Linguistics and English as a Second Language

#### San Diego State University, San Diego, CA

Bachelor of Arts in General Humanities. Minor in German

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude with Distinction in Humanities.
- Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society Member.